# JACK GRACIE

# London/Cambridge

**PERSONAL DETAILS** 

Site: jackgracie.co.uk Email: jack.c.gracie@gmail.com LinkedIn: http://linkd.in/1mzLcQ7 Contact No: 07842 907617

#### **PROFILE**

I have been working in video editing and production for six years, and in the industry for four. In my spare time I mainly focus on writing, as well as photography for events, such as festivals or weddings. I also try to take up any creative opportunity that'll give me the chance to learn something new.

#### **EDUCATION**

Sept 2013 - May 2016

Sept 2011 - June 2013

**Southampton University** 

2:1 - BA English Literature

Hills Road Sixth Form College, Cambridge

A Level (A\* - B) Maths, English Literature, and Photography

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

August 2017 -Present

#### Metro.co.uk

- Video Journalist / Editor
- Edited 240+ videos totalling over 35 million views.
- Currently in the process of researching and producing original shortform documentaries

July 2016 - May 2017

# Augmentra Ltd.

- Video Content Producer
- Created a series of short documentaries to help promote the app 'ViewRanger' to new customers and its existing 3 million user base.
- Shot, edited, colour graded, sound mixed, audio repaired all episodes
- Designed the graphics and style of the series.
- Additionally edited trailers for app updates, aided promotional team in preparations for reveal at Apple iPhone 7 Keynote, and updated website and app designs.

May 2015 - July 2016

# The Edge Magazine

- Head of Graphic Design
- Writer of 70+ articles covering Film, Music, TV, and Events.
- Designed 7 complete issues and additional promotional material, nominated at SPA Awards for Best Design.

July 2015 – June 2015

# Ella Doran Design

- Assistant Designer Creating print texture designs.
- Paid by UoS Excel Placement Program for internship, taken on as freelance following end of program.
- Work created has since been featured in The Guardian, Elle, Warehouse Home, Paper Chase FX, and Milk Decoration magazine.

May 2015 - July 2015

The National Student

Writer/ Interviewer / Video Editor

November 2014 -Present

## Reel Opinions (Online Show)

- Co-host, Producer, Interviewer, Editor 300+ episodes
- Head of PR communicating and negotiation with various agencies for interviews and review screeners.
- In charge of website, YouTube channel, Twitter, Facebook, Tumblr.

September 2014

#### Publicis Chemistry Advertising firm, London – Intern

- Aiding in construction of an EE advertising campaign
- Working with both the creative and graphics teams

May 2012 - May 2014

- Multiple Film Shorts Personal & Business
  - Various roles -Writer/Director/Cinematographer/Editor/Colourist/VFX
    - http://www.imdb.com/name/nm7162700/

## **EMPLOYMENT**

August 2015

# Lovely Day Productions - Runner

- Runner for 'Grantchester'
- Took charge of 20+ extras, and tracked costume changes.

July - Sept 2014

Yo!Sushi - Front of House

Working in a hectic, fast paced environment for long shifts.

Working with customers from behind the till and around the shop

Oct 2012 – Aug N

- National Trust Sales Assistant
  - Organising, checking and finding stock

#### **SKILLS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

Skills

#### Advanced in

- Microsoft Office, iWork, and Google Doc formats.
- Wordpress
- Avid Media Composer, Final Cut Pro.
- Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Premier Pro, and After Effects
- Audacity, Adobe Audition, iZotope RX4.
- Davinci Resolve 12.5
- Advance technical knowledge of YouTube/Vimeo

#### Useful

- Freelance portrait, event, and on-set photography (Weddings, Latitude Festival, TEDx Talks)
- Sound operation with Rode/Zoom products
- Blender, Cinema 4D, 3Ds Max
- Knowledge of HTML/CSS and Java
- Filezilla, Episode, Aegisub, and other subtitling programs.
- Experience in promotion on all social media platforms and SEO.

Achievements

#### **Achievements**

- Editor of over 300+ YouTube videos collecting over 170,000 views
- Listed in Fandor's 'Best Video Essays of 2016'.
- Started and built relationships with numerous UK Film PR companies, leading to aiding the UK promotion of several feature films and events (London Film Festival, Sundance UK, Free Fire, Sicario, Anomalisa, Brooklyn, The Program)
- Designer of seven printed entertainment magazines

# **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

I enjoy writing, having successfully taken part in the Nanowrimo contest by writing a full 50,000+ word novel in under a month. I also have written several short and feature screenplays and currently writing a feature script.

I was a volunteer at my university TV station, SUSUTV, which lead me to take part in multiple short films and later establish Reel Opinions. Since its inception the project has become a true passion of mine, allowing me to express my love of Film and TV whilst branching out into new skills, such as podcasting, live broadcasting, and building a network of contacts.

Once took an online quiz and am now an ordained priest of Dudeism. Have never had a need for this, and probably never will.

# **REFERENCES**

Available upon request